Guide to the William Graham Sumner Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1854-(1863-1909)-1948; Series I; 14' (36 boxes)
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Woodruff, George D., Jr. - Virginia Woodward, 1882-1885, 1887, 1889, 1891, 1895, 1906 (Box 31, Folder 858)
    - Woolen, Evans (*), 1887-1900, undated (Box 31, Folder 859)
    - Wooley, N. H. - Rene Worms, 1874, 1877, 1880-1881, 1884, 1886, 1893, 1897-1899, 1906-1907, undated (Box 31, Folder 860)
    - Wright, A. J. - Elizabeth E. Wright, 1884-1885, 1896, 1903-1904, undated (Box 31, Folder 861)
    - Wright, George L., 1870-1877 (Box 31, Folder 862)
    - Wright, Henry P. (*), 1886-1908 (Box 31, Folder 863)
    - Wright, H. E. - Wyman, 1883, 1885, 1891, 1896, 1901, undated (Box 31, Folder 864)
    - Yaggy, A. F. - Yale Alumni Association of Philadelphia, 1875-1876, 1882-1885, 1887-1888, 1890, 1893, 1895, 1901, 1903, undated (Box 31, Folder 865)
    - Yale Alumni Weekly - Yale Union, 1875, 1877, 1881, 1885, 1888, 1895-1896, 1898-1900, 1903-1904, 1907-1909 (Box 31, Folder 866)
    - Yale University Christian Association - Tetsutaro Yoshida, 1893, 1897, 1900-1901, 1903-1904, 1906, 1908, undated (Box 31, Folder 867)
    - Yardley, Laura (*), undated (Box 31, Folder 868-869)
    - Yergason, H. C. - L. W. Youmans, 1878, 1882-1884, 1887, 1889-1890, 1909 (Box 31, Folder 870)
    - Youmans, William Jay (*), 1886, 1889, 1896-1898, 1900 (Box 31, Folder 871)
    - The Young Churchman Co. - Edward Young, 1869, 1874-1875, 1880, 1884-1886, 1890, 1901, 1906-1908 (Box 31, Folder 872)
    - Young, Mason (*), 1872-1884 (Box 31, Folder 873)
    - Young, Thomas - Augustus Zilger, 1876, 1880, 1884, 1890 (Box 31, Folder 874)
    - Unidentified (Box 32, Folder 875-890)
  - Incoming Correspondence: Not to Sumner
    - A - C, 1870, 1873, 1883-1884, 1901, 1904, 1922 (Box 33, Folder 891)
    - D - G, 1868, 1869, 1875, 1886, 1888, 1897, 1899, 1904, 1908, 1920, 1924, undated (Box 33, Folder 892)
    - H - O, 1870, 1874, 1877, 1878, 1886-1887, 1901, 1906, 1921, undated (Box 33, Folder 893)
    - P - R, 1866, 1868-1869, 1873, 1904, 1906, 1915, undated (Box 33, Folder 894)
    - Se - St, 1872, 1878, 1901, 1924 (Box 33, Folder 895)
    - Sumner, Diana - Graham Sumner, 1890, 1909, 1910, undated (Box 33, Folder 896)
    - Sumner, Jeannie, 1886, 1896, 1898, 1909-1910, undated (Box 33, Folder 896a-b)
    - Sumner, Jeannie, to Eliot and Diana Sumner (*), 1906-1916 undated (Box 33, Folder 896c)
    - T, 1924, undated (Box 33, Folder 897)
    - V - Y, 1870, 1872, 1878, 1886, 1897 (Box 33, Folder 898)
    - Letters of condolence to Eliot and Diana Sumner on the death of W.G. Sumner, 1910, undated (Box 33, Folder 898a)
    - Unidentified, 1868-1869, 1871, 1887-1888, 1891, 1898-1900, 1916, undated (Box 33, Folder 899)
  - Incoming Correspondence: To Jeannie Sumner
    - A - C, 1870, 1897, 1910, undated (Box 34, Folder 900)
    - D - E, 1868, 1870-1871, 1873-1874, 1876, 1880, 1887, 1910, 1913, undated (Box 34, Folder 901)
    - F - J, 1870, 1872, 1881-1882, 1910, undated (Box 34, Folder 902)
    - K - P, 1870, 1883, 1910, 1912-1914, undated (Box 34, Folder 903)
    - R - Wa, 1876, 1884, 1907, 1910, undated (Box 34, Folder 904)
    - We - Wo, unidentified, 1870, 1910, undated (Box 34, Folder 905)
    - Elliott, Frederic B., 1868-1871, 1872, 1879-1882, 1884, 1900-1901, 1905, 1908, undated (Box 34, Folder 906-908)
    - Elliott, Julia, 1871, 1900, undated (Box 34, Folder 909)
    - Sumner, Alice, undated (Box 34, Folder 910)
    - Sumner, Eliot, 1890, 1896-1899, 1900 January -Jul, 1900 October - 1901 Dec, 1903-1904, 1906, 1908, undated (Box 34, Folder 911-914)
    - Sumner, Graham, 1890, 1897, 1901, 1903, 1908, undated (Box 34, Folder 915-916)
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - 1862 Oct; 1868 July - September (Box 35, Folder 917)
    - 1864 January (Box 35, Folder 918)
    - 1864 April - August (Box 35, Folder 919)
    - 1864 November - December (Box 35, Folder 920)
    - 1866 March - Jul, October - Nov, 1867 January (Box 35, Folder 921)
    - 1868 March - August (Box 35, Folder 922)
    - 1870, 1873 (Box 35, Folder 923)
    - 1874 January - October (Box 35, Folder 924)
    - 1875 January - October (Box 35, Folder 925)
    - 1876 March - 1878 April (Box 35, Folder 926)
    - 1882 - 1885, 1887, 1891 (Box 35, Folder 927)
    - 1904 June - Nov, 1905 July - August (Box 35, Folder 933)
    - 1892 May - June (Box 35, Folder 928)
    - 1893 - 1894 (Box 35, Folder 929)
    - 1896 - 1899 (Box 35, Folder 930)
    - 1900 January - 1901 September (Box 35, Folder 931)
    - 1902 June - 1903 October (Box 35, Folder 932)
    - 1906 January - December (Box 35, Folder 934)
    - 1907 (Box 35, Folder 935)
    - 1908 March - December (Box 35, Folder 936)
    - 1909 January - November (Box 35, Folder 937-938)
    - undated (Box 35, Folder 939)
    - W.G. Sumner to Eliot and Diana Sumner (*), 1897-1909, undated (Box 35, Folder 939a)
  - W. G. Sumner to Jeannie Elliott
    - Typed letter (copies), 1870 April 24 - June 12, 1870 June 14 - 1871 May 14 (Box 36, Folder 940-942)
    - 1870 April 24 - May 27 (Box 36, Folder 943-947)
    - 1870 June 6 - 17 (Box 36, Folder 948-949)
    - 1870 June 13 - 20, 1870 July 5 - 9 (Box 36, Folder 950-951)
    - 1870 July 11 - August 4 (Box 36, Folder 952-953)
    - 1870 August 6 - 12, 1870 August 13 - 30, 1870 September 16 - 23 (Box 36, Folder 954-956)
    - 1870 September 25 - October 13 (Box 36, Folder 957-959)
    - 1870 October 20 - November 5, 1871 March 14 (Box 36, Folder 960-961)
- Writings, 1859-1940; Series II; 43' plus 32 drawers of notecards (77 boxes and 1 folio)
  Series II has nine categories or sections: Articles, Essays, Books, Sermons, Addresses and Lectures, Notebooks, Subject Files, Miscellaneous Writings, and Notecards, Indexes, and Booklists.
  Each section is arranged chronologically except Subject Files. This section consists primarily of unbound scrapbooks, each separately contained within one box. For a further explanation, see page 9.
  - Articles
    - "Politics in America, 1776-1876" North American Review (printed), 1876 January (Box 37, Folder 962)
    - "Is the War Over?" New York World (TMs), 1876 October 9 (Box 37, Folder 963)
    - "Bourbonism" New York World (TMs), 1876 October 16 (Box 37, Folder 964)
    - "What Has Become of Reform" New York World (TMs), 1876 October 23 (Box 37, Folder 965)
    - Sumner's reply to Charles P. Ingersoll, New York Herald (printed), 1876 November 22 (Box 37, Folder 966)
    - "Socialism" Scribner's Monthly (TMs), 1878 (Box 37, Folder 967)
    - "The Theory and Practice of Elections" Princeton Review (TMs), 1880 March (Box 37, Folder 968)
    - "The Theory and Practice of Elections" Princeton Review (printed), 1880 March (Box 37, Folder 969)
    - "Presidential Elections and Civil Service Reform" Princeton Review (TMs), 1881 January (Box 37, Folder 970)
    - "Presidential Elections and Civil Service Reform" Princeton Review (printed), 1881 January (Box 37, Folder 971)
    - "The Argument Against Protective Taxes" Princeton Review (TMs), 1881 March (Box 37, Folder 972)
    - "The Argument Against Protective Taxes" Princeton Review (printed), 1881 March (Box 37, Folder 973)
    - "Shall Americans Own Ships?" North American Review (TMs), 1881 June (Box 37, Folder 974)
    - "Shall Americans Own Ships?" North American Review (printed), 1881 June (Box 37, Folder 975)
    - "Sociology" Princeton Review (printed), 1881 November (Box 37, Folder 976)
    - "Wages" Princeton Review (TMs), 1882 July (Box 37, Folder 977)
    - "Protective Taxes and Wages" North American Review (printed), 1883 March (Box 37, Folder 978)
    - Letter to the Editor (AMs), 1883 May 17 (Box 37, Folder 979)
    - "Our Colleges Before the Country" Princeton Review (printed), 1884 March (Box 37, Folder 980)
    - "Sociological Fallacies" North American Review (printed), 1884 June (Box 37, Folder 981)
    - "Evils of the Tariff System" North American Review (printed), 1884 September (Box 37, Folder 982)
    - "On the Freedom of Contract" Science (printed), 1886 March 5 (Box 37, Folder 983)
    - "Industrial war" (fragment) Forum (printed), 1886 September (Box 37, Folder 984)
    - "Mr. Blaine on the Tariff" North American Review (printed), 1886 October (Box 37, Folder 985)
    - "What Makes the Rich Richer and the Poor Poorer" Popular Science Monthly (printed), 1887 January (Box 37, Folder 986)
    - "The Indians in 1887" Forum (TMs), 1887 May (Box 37, Folder 987)
    - "The Indians in 1887" Forum (TMs), 1887 May (Box 37, Folder 988)
    - "Strikes and the Industrial Organization" Popular Science Monthly (TMs), 1887 July (Box 37, Folder 989)
    - "Strikes and the Industrial Organization" Popular Science Monthly (printed), 1887 July (Box 37, Folder 990)
    - "State Interference" North American Review (printed), 1887 August (Box 37, Folder 991)
    - "Civil Service Reform" Chatauquan (printed), 1887 November (Box 37, Folder 992)
    - "The Fall in Silver and International Competition" Rand-McNally Banker's Monthly (printed), 1888 February (Box 37, Folder 993)
    - "The First Steps Toward a Millennium" Cosmopolitan (printed), 1888 March (Box 37, Folder 994)
    - "Tariff Reform" Independent (TMs), 1888 August 16 (Box 37, Folder 995)
    - "Sketch of William Graham Sumner" Popular Science Monthly (printed), 1889 June (Box 37, Folder 996)
    - "An Old Trust" Independent (TMs), 1889 June 13 (Box 37, Folder 997)
    - "What is Civil Liberty?" Popular Science Monthly (printed), 1889 July (Box 37, Folder 998)
    - "Do We Want Industrial Peace?" Forum (printed), 1889 December (Box 37, Folder 999)
    - "Why I Am a Free Trader" Twentieth Century (printed), 1890 April 24 (Box 37, Folder 1000)
    - Liberté des Echanges, Nouveau Dictionnaire d'Economie Politique, Vol. 2 (printed), 1891 (Box 37, Folder 1001)
    - "Professor Sumner on Tariff Reform" New York Herald (printed), 1892 November - 1893 January (?) (Box 37, Folder 1002)
    - "Professor Sumner on Yale" Yale News (printed), 1896 January 20 (Box 37, Folder 1003)
    - "The Treasury as a Bank of Issue and a Silver Warehouse" The Bond Record (AMs), 1896 March (Box 37, Folder 1004)
    - "The Treasury as a Bank of Issue and a Silver Warehouse" The Bond Record (printed), 1896 March (Box 37, Folder 1005)
    - Letter to the Editor Yale Alumni Weekly (printed), 1896 May 20 (Box 37, Folder 1006)
    - "The Fallacy of Territorial Expansion" Forum (printed), 1896 June (Box 37, Folder 1007)
    - "Policy of Debasement" New York Journal (printed), 1896 July 29 (Box 37, Folder 1008)
    - "The Proposed Dual Organization of Mankind" Popular Science Monthly (printed), 1896 August (Box 37, Folder 1009)
    - "Prosperity Strangled by Gold" Leslie's Weekly (printed), 1896 August 20 (Box 37, Folder 1010)
    - "Cause and Cure of Hard Times" Leslie's Weekly (printed), 1896 September 3 (Box 37, Folder 1011)
    - "The Free-Coinage Scheme is Impractical at Every Point" Leslie's Weekly (printed), 1896 September 10 (Box 37, Folder 1012)
    - "The Delusion of the Debtors" Leslie's Weekly (printed), 1896 September 17 (Box 37, Folder 1013)
    - "The Crime of 1873" Leslie's Weekly (printed), 1896 September 24 (Box 37, Folder 1014)
    - "The Single Gold Standard" Chatauquan (printed), 1896 October (Box 38, Folder 1015)
    - "Banks of Issue in the United States" Forum (printed), 1896 October (Box 38, Folder 1016)
    - "The Spanish Dollar and the Colonial Shilling" American Historical Review (AMs), 1898 (Box 38, Folder 1017)
    - "The Spanish Dollar and the Colonial Shilling" American Historical Review (TMs), 1898 (Box 38, Folder 1018)
    - "Lieter Has Been a Hero" World (printed), 1898 June 15 (Box 38, Folder 1019)
    - "The Conquest of the United States by Spain" Yale Law Journal (AMs), 1899 January (Box 38, Folder 1020)
    - "The Conquest of the United States by Spain" Yale Law Journal (printed), 1899 January (Box 38, Folder 1021)
    - "The Conquest of the United States by Spain" Yale Law Journal (printed), 1899 January (Box 38, Folder 1022)
    - Book review of Die Feldgemeinschaft in Russland, Yale Review (AMs), 1899 May (Box 38, Folder 1023)
    - "The Coin Shilling of Massachusetts Bay" Yale Review (AMs), 1898 November - 1899 February (Box 38, Folder 1024)
    - "The Coin Shilling of Massachusetts Bay" Yale Review (early draft) (AMs), 1898 November - 1899 February, 1898 November - 1899 February (Box 38, Folder 1025-1026)
    - "First Fruits of Expansion" Evening Post (printed), 1900 April 14 (Box 38, Folder 1027)
    - "Suicidal Fanaticism in Russia" Popular Science Monthly (AMs), 1901 November - 1902 April (Box 38, Folder 1028)
    - "Suicidal Fanaticism in Russia" Popular Science Monthly (TMs), 1901 November - 1902 April (Box 38, Folder 1029)
    - "The Family and Social Change" American Journal of Sociology (AMs), 1909 March (Box 38, Folder 1030)
    - "The Family and Social Change" American Journal of Sociology (TMs), 1909 March (Box 38, Folder 1031)
    - "The Status of Women in Chaldea, Egypt, India, Judea and Greece to the Time of Christ" Forum (AMs), 1909 August (Box 38, Folder 1032)
    - "The Mores of the Present and Future" Yale Review (AMs), 1909 November (Box 38, Folder 1033)
    - "The Mores of the Present and Future" Yale Review (TMs), 1909 November (Box 38, Folder 1034-1035)
    - "Religion and the Mores" American Journal of Sociology (TMs), 1910 March (Box 38, Folder 1036-1037)
    - "Witchcraft" Forum (proofsheets), 1909 or 1910 (Box 38, Folder 1037a)
    - "Professor Sumner's Views", undated (Box 38, Folder 1038)
    - "Decline of Confidence Due to Reckless Denunciation" New York Herald, undated (Box 38, Folder 1039)
  - Essays
    General note
    See also: Folio
    - "The Church's Law of the Interpretation of Scripture" (AMs), 1872 April 3 (Box 39, Folder 1040)
    - "Introductory Essay" to Sumner's translation of K.C.W.F. Bahr's The Book of Kings (AMs), 1872(?) (Box 39, Folder 1041)
    - "The Lesson of the Panic" (AMs), 1874 (Box 39, Folder 1042)
    - "Taxation" (AMs), 1874(?) (Box 39, Folder 1043)
    - "The Strikes" (AMs), 1877(?) (Box 39, Folder 1044)
    - "The Strikes" (TMs), 1877(?) (Box 39, Folder 1045)
    - "Definitions and Elementary Principles of Economic Science" (AMs), 1878 March 21 (?) (Box 39, Folder 1046)
    - "Definitions and Elementary Principles of Economic Science" (TMs), 1878 March 21 (?) (Box 39, Folder 1047-1048)
    - "Relation of Legislation to Currency" (AMs), 1878 (Box 39, Folder 1049)
    - "The Commercial Crisis of 1837" (AMs), 1877 or 1878 (Box 39, Folder 1050)
    - "Amortissement of Public Debts" (AMs), 1879 (Box 39, Folder 1051)
    - "The Financial Questions Now Before Us" (AMs), 1880(?) (Box 39, Folder 1052)
    - "A Parable" (AMs), 1880 - 1889 (?) (Box 39, Folder 1053)
    - "Socialism" or "The Challenge of Facts" (AMs), 1880 - 1889 (Box 39, Folder 1054)
    - "Socialism" (AMs), 1880 - 1889 (Box 39, Folder 1055)
    - "Laissez-Faire" (TMs), 1885 - 1889 (Box 39, Folder 1056)
    - "Free Trade" (TMs), 1889 (Box 39, Folder 1057)
    - "Peasants and Land Tenure in Scandinavia" (AMs), 1889(?) (Box 39, Folder 1058)
    - "Peasants and Land Tenure in Scandinavia" (TMs), 1889(?) (Box 39, Folder 1059)
    - "The Mediaeval Doctrine About Commerce" (TMs), 1889 (Box 39, Folder 1060)
    - "Advancing Social and Political Organization in the United States" (AMs), 1896 - 1897 (?) (Box 39, Folder 1061)
    - "Banking in the United States" (AMs), 1898(?) (Box 40, Folder 1062)
    - "Some Words on Financial Crisis" (AMs), 1900(?) (Box 40, Folder 1063)
    - "Some Words on Financial Crisis" (TMs), 1900(?) (Box 40, Folder 1064)
    - "Purposes and Consequences" (AMs), 1900 - 1906 (Box 40, Folder 1065)
    - "Rights"(AMs), 1900 - 1906 (Box 40, Folder 1066)
    - "Rights" (TMs), 1900 - 1906 (Box 40, Folder 1067)
    - "The Bequests of the Nineteenth Century to the Twentieth" (AMs), 1901 (Box 40, Folder 1068)
    - "The Bequests of the Nineteenth Century to the Twentieth" (TMs), 1901 (Box 40, Folder 1069)
    - On the Status of Women (AMs), 1903 November 14 (Box 40, Folder 1069a)
    - "The Church and the Mores" (AMs), undated (Box 40, Folder 1070)
    - "Democratization of Industry" (TMs), undated (Box 40, Folder 1071)
    - "Free Trade" (TMs), undated (Box 40, Folder 1072)
    - "Demonism" (AMs), undated (Box 40, Folder 1073)
    - "Demonism" (TMs), undated (Box 40, Folder 1074-1075)
    - "The Marriage Institution" (AMs), undated (Box 40, Folder 1076)
    - "The Marriage Institution" (TMs), undated (Box 40, Folder 1077)
    - "Mores of the Middle Ages" (AMs), undated (Box 40, Folder 1078)
    - "Mores of the Middle Ages" (TMs), undated (Box 40, Folder 1079)
    - On Mores and Progress (AMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1080)
    - "Mores and Science" (AMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1081)
    - "Mores and Statistics and Mathematics" (AMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1082)
    - "Mores and Statistics and Mathematics" (TMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1083)
    - "Operation of Inquis:1275-1350" (AMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1084)
    - "Operation of Inquis:1275-1350" (TMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1085-1086)
    - "Patriotism and the Monroe Doctrine" (AMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1087)
    - "Patriotism and the Monroe Doctrine" (TMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1088)
    - "Status of Women in Germany" (AMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1089)
    - "Status of Women in Germany" (TMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1090)
    - "The Status of Women at Rome" (AMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1091)
    - "The Status of Women at Rome" (TMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1092-1093)
    - "Wampum" (AMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1094)
    - "Wampum" (TMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1095)
    - "We Think" (TMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1096)
    - "Witchcraft" (AMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1097-1098)
    - "Witchcraft" (TMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1099)
    - Untitled essay on Evolution, undated (Box 41, Folder 1099a)
    - Essay fragment on Demonology and Exorcism (AMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1100)
    - Essay fragment on Minority Representation (AMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1101)
    - Essay fragment on "Group Character" (AMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1102)
    - Essay fragment on "Eng. 18th Ct." (AMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1103)
    - Essay fragment on "Modern Russia" (AMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1104)
    - Essay fragment on "Credulity M.A." (AMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1105)
    - Essay fragment on "Banks and Money" (AMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1106)
    - Essay fragment on "The Archaic and the Novel in Ethnography" (AMs), undated (Box 41, Folder 1107)
    - Essay fragment on The State (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1108)
    - Essay fragment on Mohammed (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1109)
    - Essay fragment on Egypt (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1110)
    - Essay fragment on Irania (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1111)
    - Essay fragment on Religion Interfering with Effort and Satisfaction (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1112)
    - Essay fragment on China and Korea (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1113)
    - Essay fragment on Sanctions (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1114)
    - Essay fragment on the Law of Population (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1115)
    - Essay fragment on Parents and Children (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1116)
    - Essay fragment on India (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1117)
    - Essay fragment on the Renaissance (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1118)
    - Essay fragment on Shamans (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1119)
    - Essay fragment on the Bible and the Mores (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1120)
    - Essay fragment on Norway and Denmark (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1121)
    - Essay fragment on the 16th Century Schism (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1122)
    - Essay fragment on Covenant Blood (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1123)
    - Essay fragment on Marriage (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1124)
    - Essay fragment on Mores and Taboo (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1125)
    - Essay fragment on Individuation and Genesis (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1126)
    - Essay fragment on 16th and 17th Century Russia (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1127)
    - Essay fragment on French Mores During the 18th Century (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1128)
    - Essay fragment on Thargelia (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1129)
    - Essay fragment on A Poem by Niekrassoff (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1130)
    - Essay fragment on Sex Taboo (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1131)
    - Essay fragment on the Status of Women (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1132)
    - Essay fragment on Slavery in the Middle Ages (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1133)
    - Essay fragment on Indulgences (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1134)
    - Essay fragment on Heroes and Heroines in the Middle Ages (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1135)
    - Essay fragment on Sorcery (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1136)
    - Essay fragment on Slavery (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1137)
    - Essay fragment on the Modern Family (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1138)
    - Essay fragment on Demonism in Chaldea (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1139)
    - Essay fragment on Sacrifice (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1140)
    - Essay fragment on the "Chosen People" (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1141)
    - Essay fragment on Zoroaster and Egypt (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1142)
    - Essay fragment on Marx (AMs), undated (Box 42, Folder 1143)
  - Books
    - Unpublished: History of Paper Money, I. Book, 1873 (Box 43, Folder 1144)
    - Andrew Jackson as a Public Man
      - Proof sheets with W.G.S.'s corrections. Chapters I-III, 1882 (Box 43, Folder 1145)
      - Proof sheets with W.G.S.'s corrections. Chapters IV-VI, 1882 (Box 43, Folder 1146)
      - Proof sheets with W.G.S.'s corrections. Chapters VII-VIII, 1882 (Box 43, Folder 1147)
      - Proof sheets with W.G.S.'s corrections. Chapters IX-X, 1882 (Box 43, Folder 1148)
      - Proof sheets with W.G.S.'s corrections. Chapters XI-XII, 1882 (Box 43, Folder 1149)
    - History of Paper Money in American Colonies
      - (Unpublished book), undated (Box 44, Folder 1150)
      - (Unpublished book), undated (Box 44, Folder 1151-1161)
    - A History of Banking in the United States (TMs), 1896 (Box 45, Folder 1162)
    - Rough draft for Chapter I of Folkways (AMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1163)
    - Rough draft for Chapter IV of Folkways (AMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1164)
    - Fragment of rough draft for Chapter IV of Folkways (AMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1165)
    - Rough draft for Chapter V of Folkways (AMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1166)
    - Rough draft for Chapter V of Folkways (TMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1167)
    - Rough draft for Chapter VII of Folkways (AMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1168)
    - Rough draft for Chapter VIII of Folkways (TMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1169)
    - Rough draft of a portion of Chapter IX of Folkways (AMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1170)
    - Portion of rough draft for Chapter XI of Folkways (AMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1171)
    - Portion of rough draft for Chapter XI of Folkways (TMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1172)
    - Portion of rough draft for Chapter XI of Folkways (AMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1173)
    - Portion of rough draft for Chapter XIV of Folkways (AMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1174)
    - Portion of rough draft for Chapter XIV of Folkways (AMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1175)
    - Portion of rough draft for Chapter XV of Folkways (AMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1176)
    - Rough draft for Chapter XV of Folkways (AMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1177)
    - Rough draft for Chapter XVII of Folkways (AMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1178)
    - Rough draft for Chapter XVII of Folkways (TMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1179-1180)
    - Portion of rough draft for Chapter XIX of Folkways (AMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1181)
    - Portion of rough draft for Chapter XIX of Folkways (AMs), undated (Box 46, Folder 1182)